Yatharth Singh

J 9022142210 ■ yathart.singh123@gmail.com ☐ LinkedIn ☐ GitHub

Profile summary

Agile and versatile professional with 15+ months experience diverse background spanning in Product, BFSI, Food & Beverage and Consulting. Proven skills in Python, SQL & range of BI tools & improving top line bottom line of businesses.

Technical Skills

Languages & Databases: Python, R, SQL, MongoDB

Libraries & Frameworks: Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, SciPy TensorFlow Other Tools: PowerBI, Looker Studio, Tableau, Microsoft office suite.

Work Experience

GoKwik Oct 2023 - Present

Data Analyst WFH

• Automated entire HR database & created real-time analytics dashboard, ensuring seamless intergration of new data, with continuous synchronization and analysis of **2000**+ records.

- Optimized recruitment analytics, reducing time-to-fill by 23% and slashing recruitment costs by 30% within a quarter.
- More details after project completion.

Edelweiss Tokio Life Insurance

June 2023 - August 2023

Summer Intern - Dataverse Project

Mumbai

- Streamlined 350+ reports across departments by 53%, minimizing duplication & enhancing report efficiency.
- Developed interactive dashboards to oversee vital insurance KPI's like APE's, Renewal rates, Persistency & so on driving a 7% upgrade in policy renewal rates and a 14% increase in persistency.
- Prepared BRDs and other logics for 20+ new investment and life insurance products like Term Protect, Flexi-Saving Plan, ULIP's etc.

MasterChow Feb 2023 - May 2023

Data Analyst

Mumbai

- Created comprehensive dashboards utilizing AOV and Bucket analysis to track customer behaviour across 200+ cities, 63+ SKU's, resulting in a 12% increase in revenue.
- Conducted Hourly Heat map analysis to identify peak traffic periods resulting in a 28% increase in conversion rates.
- Developed analytical MIS reports for 4+ sales funnels, analysing 13+ cross-functional datasets.

Tag8.in Feb 2022 - Aug 2022

Data Analyst

Mumbai

- Optimised the inventory using 60-30-10 model to meet demand and keep logistics low and avoid stock outs, overstocking, and backorders.
- Analyzed customer reviews from Google play store using Text analysis, VADER model, and NLP.
- Developed a realtime dashboard tracking KPIs of live Drop locations, leading to an 8% rise in on-time deliveries and reduced Dwell times.
- Created PowerBI reports using DAX for HDFC, McKinsey, and Waycool, delivering actionable insights and visualizations.

Education

Veermata Jijabai Technical Institute

Feb 2020 - May 2024

B. Tech - Mechanical Engineering - 7.11

Mumbai

Vidyaniketan Jr. College

March 2020

HSC board - 76.92

Mumbai

St. Joseph High School

March 2018

SSC Board - 81.6

Mumbai

Other Achievements

Letter Of Recommendation from Founder of MasterChow & Tag8.in

98.6206 %le - MHT-CET, 92.8088 %le - JEE MAINS

Interests

Fitness Enthusiast, Performing at Open Mics on weekends and Playing Piano.